[Music]
hello friends
welcome back to our channel
i am your tosca instructor and my name
is kumaresh
i have total 14 years of it experience
in software development and test
automation
thank you
for connecting with us
hope you are doing well
[Music]
let's start our today's session
through this video i will explain the
overview of tosca buffers
and standard modules which are used to
manage buffers
the explanation of usage of tosca
buffers will be done through
demonstration
buffer is acted like variables to store
the values during execution
the stored values are also available
after completion of execution
the scope of buffer is restricted to the
local workspace only as the buffer value
cannot be updated to shared repository
[Music]
the syntax of buffer to read the value
is b buffer underscore name buffer can
be created by using action mode as
buffer for any test step where buffer
name should be the test step value
instead of using set buffer module
also using xb buffer underscore name
buffer can be created from a
verification test step dynamical
tosca provides four standard modules to
works with buffers which are available
under the path standard modules buffer
operations in modules section
the standard modules are
t-box set buffer this module is used to
create the buffer as per the name
provided in the attribute section
the value provided in the attributes
value section will be stored in the
buffer
we can create more than one buffers
using this module
t-box name to buffer this module is used
to store the test case name into the
buffer for which name is provided in the
attribute value field
we need to execute the test case from
the execution list to store the test
case name
otherwise it will store as scratchbook
t-box partial buffer this module is used
to extract the partial text and store it
to another buffer
t-box delete buffer it's used to delete
the existing buffers
the buffer name should be mentioned in
the attributes value section
[Music]
i will now show how to work with buffers
we will start with box set buffer to
create and assign values
first we will go to the buffer operation
folder in module section
all the standards modules which are
related to buffers are listed here
now selecting tbox set buffer module and
drag and drop it to the test case
provide the name of buffer as mybuffer1
by renaming the test step attribute
[Music]
we can enter any text in value column of
the test step to assign it to the buffer
now we will execute this step in
scratchbook to create the buffer as
mybuffer1 and assign value as abcde
the temporary execution log shows the
creation of buffer with value assignment
it can view from buffer viewer wizard
now we will understand the module t-box
name to buffer
first we will drag and drop it to our
test case
entering the buffer name in value column
which will be assigned the test case
name
let's use the buffermybuffer1 which was
just created
we will execute this step in scratchbook
to store test case name into
buffermybuffer1
in this case textscratchbook will be
assigned as it was executed from
scratchbook
we need to execute an execution list to
assign the actual test name
[Music]
next we will see the usage of the module
tbox partial buffer
we will drag and drop it to our test
case
we need to provide values for four
attributes
the buffer which will be assigned the
extracted text has to be provided in
buffer attribute
we are providing mybuffer2
value attribute should be the source
from which we are going to extract
partial texts
we can use the previously created buffer
mybuffer1 as the source of string which
contains abcde
the syntax to use the existing buffer as
the input value is b mybuffer1
start denotes the start position and
then denotes the end position of the
text to be extracted
we will execute the test in scratchbook
to store the extracted values to
buffermybuffer2
here extractedtext should be bcd which
is starting from second to fourth
position of the source value abcde
we can check it from buffer viewer
here the last attribute is used alone to
extract the text from the end of source
value
now we will drag and drop the last
module tbox delete buffer to remove any
existing buffer
entering the existing buffer mybuffer2
in value column
we will execute this step in scratchbook
to delete the existing mybuffer2 from
the workspace
[Music]
the the log scratch book shows that the
buffer is deleted successfully
if we see the buffer viewer the buffer
name mybuffer2 is not available now
thanks for watching this video
that's all about tosca buffers and its
usage
we will learn more about tosca test case
design features to manage test data in
next video
please visit our website lambdageeks.com
for more articles on technology
engineering mathematics and various
other domain
you can check our other website as well
[Music]
we have features like youtube trends
twitter trends
scientific calculator and many more
other tools
[Music]
if you like our video please like
comment and share
if you have any questions please comment
and we will resolve your query